DALE HOLSTEIN

704.390.8893 DHolstein30@gmail.com github.com/Zarnerz linkedin.com/in/dale-holstein

Passionate and driven web developer proficient with JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, React, Git, Node.js, AJAX, SQL, MongoDB, Handlebars and APIs. Adept analytical problem solver with experience working in a diverse work environment. Life-long learner of new technologies and constantly refining skill set.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Detail Devil

- Car detail booking web application that helps users to find detailers in their area and choose a date and time for a detailing appointment. Built using Handlebars, React, Node, Express, MongoDB, Bcrypt, Express-Sessions and Mongoose.
- Lead Back-End Developer on a team of 5
- Live-Website: https://thedetaildevil.herokuapp.com/ Repo: https://github.com/Zarnerz/Detail-Devil

NYT React

- React App that returns articles from the New York Time's API based on the user's search parameters. Built using Node, Express, MongoDB, React, Axios and Mongoose.
- Sole Developer
- Live-Website: https://nytreact-dale.herokuapp.com/ Repo: https://github.com/Zarnerz/nytreact-beta

Pic-a-Flic

- Movie selection application to help indecisive movie watchers to choose a movie to watch. User can select parameters to filter results and then has three random films returned using multiple API calls.
- Lead JavaScript & API Developer on a team of 4
- Live-Website: https://supernatmor.github.io/PADM/ Repo: https://github.com/Zarnerz/Pic-A-Flik

WORK EXPERIENCE

Crew Member - Autobell Car Wash - Indian Trail, NC

October 2015 - Present

Substitute Teacher - Boone County Schools - Madison, WV

April 2015 – September 2015

 Facilitated learning and organize learning resources to ensure students are reaching curriculum objectives.

Administrative Assistant - Bluegreen Vacations - St. Augustine, FL May 2014 - December 2014

 Provided excellent customer service, ensured accuracy and confidentiality of information, facilitated coordination between marketing and sales departments

EDUCATION

University of North Carolina at Charlotte

August 2017 - February 2018

- UNCC Coding Bootcamp Javascript Full Stack Web Development
- An intensive 24-month long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Curriculum includes: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, AJAX, APIs, Firebase, Node.js, SQL, MongoDB, Handlebars.js, Express.js, React.js, & Git.

Marshall University

December 2013 Magna Cum Laude

Bachelor of Arts: History